Klain, James M. Photographic images of Royce Hall. 1929-1998. UARC.0616
UCLA Library Special Collections
Klain, James M. Photographic images of Royce Hall.
1929-1998
UCLA Library Special Collections
Klain, James M.
UARC.0616
1.6 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Record Series 616 contains photographic images of Royce Hall at the University of California, Los Angeles, taken and assembled by James M. Klain.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729983606533
Biography/History
James M. Klain earned his Bachelor of Arts in Drama at UCLA in 1943, and although he did not obtain further degrees, continued his studies there in Theater Arts and Education. Klain went on to work at UCLA as the director of the Campus Activities Service Office, directed the renovation of Royce Hall (1982-1984), served as stage manager at such venues as the Royce Hall Auditorium and Pauley Pavilion (1947-), and held positions as charter member and Vice President of the Theater, Film and Television Alumni Association.
Scope and Content
Record Series 616 contains photographic images of Royce Hall at the University of California, Los Angeles, taken and assembled by James M. Klain. Files include color and black and white photographs, slides, color transparencies, proofs, and negatives of Royce Hall images. Additionally, this collection features collected images of Royce Hall in print, photographs of other locations on the UCLA campus, and photographs of the Watts Towers in Los Angeles, California.
This is an inactive record series; no additional University records are expected to be added.
- Exterior shots (black and white)., 1929-1932, undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Exterior shots (color)., Undated. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Interior shots (black and white)., Undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Interior shots (color)., Undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Auditorium interior., 1948, undated. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Aerial photographs., 1970, undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Construction and floorplan images., 1930, undated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Architectural details., 1929, undated. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pipe organ., Undated. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Renovations (color)., Undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Renovations (internal and external shots)., 1983. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Renovations (color)., 1983. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Events., 1929-1980, undated. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Charter Day (external, black and white) original and preservation copies., 1964. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Images of Royce Hall in print., 1968-1998. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Royce Hall book negatives and transparencies., Undated. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Photos of Royce Hall book photos., Undated. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Campus at night (black and white)., Undated. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Portraits/people., 1940, undated. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Kerckhoff Hall (color)., 1987. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Watts Towers (color)., 1985. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Proofs., 1978-1983. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Color transparencies., Undated. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Slides., 1980-1984, undated. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Slides., 1984, undated. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Negatives., Undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "Encore" book (celebrating the reopening of Royce Hall)., 1998. (Box 3, Folder 10)